<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TopQuiz</string>

    <string name="correct_answer_1">وَأُوحِىَ إِلَىٰ نُوحٍ أَنَّهُ ۥ لَن يُؤۡمِنَ مِن قَوۡمِكَ إِلَّا مَن قَدۡ ءَامَنَ فَلَا تَبۡتَٮِٕسۡ بِمَا كَانُواْ يَفۡعَلُونَ (٣٦) وَٱصۡنَعِ ٱلۡفُلۡكَ بِأَعۡيُنِنَا وَوَحۡيِنَا وَلَا تُخَـٰطِبۡنِى فِى ٱلَّذِينَ ظَلَمُوٓاْ‌ۚ إِنَّہُم مُّغۡرَقُونَ (٣٧) \n\nAnd it was revealed to Noah: “None of your people will believe, except those who have already believed, so do not grieve over what they do.” (36) “And build the Ark, under Our eyes, and with Our inspiration, and do not address Me regarding those who did wrong; they are to be drowned.” (37) \n\n[Sourate Hud, 36-37]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_2">وَلَقَدۡ أَرۡسَلۡنَا نُوحًا إِلَىٰ قَوۡمِهِۦ فَلَبِثَ فِيهِمۡ أَلۡفَ سَنَةٍ إِلَّا خَمۡسِينَ عَامً۬ا فَأَخَذَهُمُ ٱلطُّوفَانُ وَهُمۡ ظَـٰلِمُونَ (١٤) \n\nWe sent Noah to his people, and He stayed among them for a thousand years less fifty years [inviting them to believe in the Oneness of Allah (Monotheism), and discard the false gods and other deities]. Then the Deluge overtook them; for they were wrongdoers. (14)\n\n[Sourate Al-Ankabût, 14]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_3">وَإِنَّ يُونُسَ لَمِنَ ٱلۡمُرۡسَلِينَ (١٣٩) إِذۡ أَبَقَ إِلَى ٱلۡفُلۡكِ ٱلۡمَشۡحُونِ (١٤٠) فَسَاهَمَ فَكَانَ مِنَ ٱلۡمُدۡحَضِينَ (١٤١) فَٱلۡتَقَمَهُ ٱلۡحُوتُ وَهُوَ مُلِيمٌ۬ (١٤٢) \n\nAnd Jonah was one of the messengers. (139) When he ran to the laden boat. (140) He gambled and lost. (141) Then the fish swallowed him, and he was to blame. (142)\n\n[Sourate As-Sâffât, 139 to 141]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_4"> إِذۡ قَالَتِ ٱلۡمَلَـٰٓٮِٕكَةُ يَـٰمَرۡيَمُ إِنَّ ٱللَّهَ يُبَشِّرُكِ بِكَلِمَةٍ۬ مِّنۡهُ ٱسۡمُهُ ٱلۡمَسِيحُ عِيسَى ٱبۡنُ مَرۡيَمَ وَجِيهً۬ا فِى ٱلدُّنۡيَا وَٱلۡأَخِرَةِ وَمِنَ ٱلۡمُقَرَّبِينَ (٤٥) وَيُڪَلِّمُ ٱلنَّاسَ فِى ٱلۡمَهۡدِ وَڪَهۡلاً۬ وَمِنَ ٱلصَّـٰلِحِينَ (٤٦)\n\n(Remember) when the angels said: "O Maryam (Mary)! Verily, Allah gives you the glad tidings of a Word ["Be!" - and he was! i.e. 'Iesa (Jesus) the son of Maryam (Mary)] from Him, his name will be the Messiah 'Iesa (Jesus), the son of Maryam (Mary), held in honour in this world and in the Hereafter, and will be one of those who are near to Allah."(45) "He will speak to the people in the cradle and in manhood, and he will be one of the righteous." (46)\n\n[Sourate Aalee-Imrân, 45 and 46]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_5">وَلِسُلَيۡمَـٰنَ ٱلرِّيحَ غُدُوُّهَا شَہۡرٌ۬ وَرَوَاحُهَا شَہۡرٌ۬ۖ وَأَسَلۡنَا لَهُ ۥ عَيۡنَ ٱلۡقِطۡرِۖ وَمِنَ ٱلۡجِنِّ مَن يَعۡمَلُ بَيۡنَ يَدَيۡهِ بِإِذۡنِ رَبِّهِۖۦ وَمَن يَزِغۡ مِنۡہُمۡ عَنۡ أَمۡرِنَا نُذِقۡهُ مِنۡ عَذَابِ ٱلسَّعِيرِ (١٢) \n\nAnd to Solomon [We subjected] the wind - its morning [journey was that of] a month - and its afternoon [journey was that of] a month, and We made flow for him a spring of [liquid] copper. And among the jinn were those who worked for him by the permission of his Lord. And whoever deviated among them from Our command - We will make him taste of the punishment of the Blaze. (12)\n\n[Sourate Saba, 12]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_6">وَرَبُّكَ أَعۡلَمُ بِمَن فِى ٱلسَّمَـٰوَٲتِ وَٱلۡأَرۡضِ‌ۗ وَلَقَدۡ فَضَّلۡنَا بَعۡضَ ٱلنَّبِيِّـۧنَ عَلَىٰ بَعۡضٍ۬‌ۖ وَءَاتَيۡنَا دَاوُ ۥدَ زَبُورً۬ا (٥٥) \n\nAnd your Lord is most knowing of whoever is in the heavens and the earth. And We have made some of the prophets exceed others [in various ways], and to David We gave the book [of Psalms] (Zabûr) (55).\n\n[Sourate Al-Isrâ, 55]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_7">إِذۡ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلۡمَلَـٰٓٮِٕكَةِ إِنِّى خَـٰلِقُۢ بَشَرً۬ا مِّن طِينٍ۬ (٧١) فَإِذَا سَوَّيۡتُهُ ۥ وَنَفَخۡتُ فِيهِ مِن رُّوحِى فَقَعُواْ لَهُ ۥ سَـٰجِدِينَ (٧٢) فَسَجَدَ ٱلۡمَلَـٰٓٮِٕكَةُ ڪُلُّهُمۡ أَجۡمَعُونَ (٧٣) إِلَّآ إِبۡلِيسَ ٱسۡتَكۡبَرَ وَكَانَ مِنَ ٱلۡكَـٰفِرِينَ (٧٤) قَالَ يَـٰٓإِبۡلِيسُ مَا مَنَعَكَ أَن تَسۡجُدَ لِمَا خَلَقۡتُ بِيَدَىَّ‌ۖ أَسۡتَكۡبَرۡتَ أَمۡ كُنتَ مِنَ ٱلۡعَالِينَ (٧٥) \n\n(Remember) when your Lord said to the angels: "Truly, I am going to create man from clay". (71) So when I have fashioned him and breathed into him (his) soul created by Me, then you fall down prostrate to him." (72) So the angels prostrated themselves, all of them: (73) Except Iblis (Satan) he was proud and was one of the disbelievers. (74) (Allah) said: "O Iblis (Satan)! What prevents you from prostrating yourself to one whom I have created with Both My Hands. Are you too proud (to fall prostrate to Adam) or are you one of the high exalted?" (75)\n\n[Sourate Sâd, 71 to 75]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_8">وَعَلَّمَ ءَادَمَ ٱلۡأَسۡمَآءَ كُلَّهَا ثُمَّ عَرَضَہُمۡ عَلَى ٱلۡمَلَـٰٓٮِٕكَةِ فَقَالَ أَنۢبِـُٔونِى بِأَسۡمَآءِ هَـٰٓؤُلَآءِ إِن كُنتُمۡ صَـٰدِقِينَ (٣١) \n\nAnd He taught Adam all the names (of everything) , then He showed them to the angels and said, "Tell Me the names of these if you are truthful." (31)\n\n[Sourate Al-Baqara, 31]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_9">وَإِذۡ قَالَ إِبۡرَٲهِيمُ لِأَبِيهِ ءَازَرَ أَتَتَّخِذُ أَصۡنَامًا ءَالِهَةً‌ۖ إِنِّىٓ أَرَٮٰكَ وَقَوۡمَكَ فِى ضَلَـٰلٍ۬ مُّبِينٍ۬ (٧٤) \n\nAnd (remember) when Ibrahim (Abraham) said to his father Azar: "Do you take idols as aliha (gods)? Verily, I see you and your people in manifest error. " (74)\n\n[Sourate Al-An\'âm, 74]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_10">وَكَذَٰلِكَ يَجۡتَبِيكَ رَبُّكَ وَيُعَلِّمُكَ مِن تَأۡوِيلِ ٱلۡأَحَادِيثِ وَيُتِمُّ نِعۡمَتَهُ ۥ عَلَيۡكَ وَعَلَىٰٓ ءَالِ يَعۡقُوبَ كَمَآ أَتَمَّهَا عَلَىٰٓ أَبَوَيۡكَ مِن قَبۡلُ إِبۡرَٲهِيمَ وَإِسۡحَـٰقَ‌ۚ إِنَّ رَبَّكَ عَلِيمٌ حَكِيمٌ۬ (٦) \n\n"Thus will your Lord choose you and teach you the interpretation of dreams (and other things) and perfect His Favour on you and on the offspring of Ya'qub (Jacob), as He perfected it on your fathers, Ibrahim (Abraham) and Ishaque (Isaac) aforetime! Verily, your Lord is All-Knowing, All-Wise." (6)\n\n[Sourate Yûsuf, 6]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_11">وَلَمَّا دَخَلُواْ مِنۡ حَيۡثُ أَمَرَهُمۡ أَبُوهُم مَّا ڪَانَ يُغۡنِى عَنۡهُم مِّنَ ٱللَّهِ مِن شَىۡءٍ إِلَّا حَاجَةً۬ فِى نَفۡسِ يَعۡقُوبَ قَضَٮٰهَا‌ۚ وَإِنَّهُ ۥ لَذُو عِلۡمٍ۬ لِّمَا عَلَّمۡنَـٰهُ وَلَـٰكِنَّ أَڪۡثَرَ ٱلنَّاسِ لَا يَعۡلَمُونَ (٦٨) وَلَمَّا دَخَلُواْ عَلَىٰ يُوسُفَ ءَاوَىٰٓ إِلَيۡهِ أَخَاهُ‌ۖ قَالَ إِنِّىٓ أَنَا۟ أَخُوكَ فَلَا تَبۡتَٮِٕسۡ بِمَا ڪَانُواْ يَعۡمَلُونَ (٦٩) \n\nAnd when they entered according to their father\'s advice, it did not avail them in the least against (the Will of) Allah, it was but a need of Ya\'qub\'s (Jacob) inner-self which he discharged. And verily, he was endowed with knowledge because We had taught him, but most men know not.(68) And when they went in before Yusuf (Joseph), he betook his brother (Benjamin) to himself and said: "Verily!I am your brother, so grieve not for what they used to do." (69)\n\n[Sourate Yûsuf, 68 and 69]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_12">يَـٰزَڪَرِيَّآ إِنَّا نُبَشِّرُكَ بِغُلَـٰمٍ ٱسۡمُهُ ۥ يَحۡيَىٰ لَمۡ نَجۡعَل لَّهُ ۥ مِن قَبۡلُ سَمِيًّ۬ا (٧) \n\n(Allah said) "O Zakariya (Zachariah)! Verily, We give you the glad tidings of a son, His name will be Yahya (John). We have given that name to none before (him)." (7)\n\n[Sourate Maryam, 7]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_13">ثُمَّ عَرَجَ بِنَا إِلَى السَّمَاءِ الرَّابِعَةِ فَاسْتَفْتَحَ جِبْرِيلُ - عَلَيْهِ السَّلاَمُ - قِيلَ مَنْ هَذَا قَالَ جِبْرِيلُ ‏.‏\nقِيلَ وَمَنْ مَعَكَ قَالَ مُحَمَّدٌ ‏.\n‏قَالَ وَقَدْ بُعِثَ إِلَيْهِ قَالَ قَدْ بُعِثَ إِلَيْهِ ‏.\n‏فَفُتِحَ لَنَا فَإِذَا أَنَا بِإِدْرِيسَ فَرَحَّبَ وَدَعَا لِي بِخَيْرٍ قَالَ اللَّهُ عَزَّ وَجَلَّ ‏{‏ وَرَفَعْنَاهُ مَكَانًا عَلِيًّا‏} \n\nThen he ascended with us to the fourth heaven. Gabriel (peace be upon him) asked for the (gate) to be opened, and it was said: Who is he? He replied: Gabriel. It was (again) said: Who is with you? He said: Muhammad. It was said: Has he been sent for? He replied: He has indeed been sent for. The (gate) was opened for us, and lo! Idris was there. He welcomed me and prayed for my well-being. (About him) Allah, the Exalted and the Glorious, has said:" We elevated him (Idris) to the exalted position" (Sourate Maryam, 57).\n\n[Sahih Muslim, 162]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_14">  إِذۡ قَالَ ٱللَّهُ يَـٰعِيسَى ٱبۡنَ مَرۡيَمَ ٱذۡڪُرۡ نِعۡمَتِى عَلَيۡكَ وَعَلَىٰ وَٲلِدَتِكَ إِذۡ أَيَّدتُّكَ بِرُوحِ ٱلۡقُدُسِ تُكَلِّمُ ٱلنَّاسَ فِى ٱلۡمَهۡدِ وَڪَهۡلاً۬‌ۖ وَإِذۡ عَلَّمۡتُكَ ٱلۡڪِتَـٰبَ وَٱلۡحِكۡمَةَ وَٱلتَّوۡرَٮٰةَ وَٱلۡإِنجِيلَ‌ۖ وَإِذۡ تَخۡلُقُ مِنَ ٱلطِّينِ كَهَيۡـَٔةِ ٱلطَّيۡرِ بِإِذۡنِى فَتَنفُخُ فِيہَا فَتَكُونُ طَيۡرَۢا بِإِذۡنِى‌ۖ وَتُبۡرِئُ ٱلۡأَڪۡمَهَ وَٱلۡأَبۡرَصَ بِإِذۡنِى‌ۖ وَإِذۡ تُخۡرِجُ ٱلۡمَوۡتَىٰ بِإِذۡنِى‌ۖ وَإِذۡ ڪَفَفۡتُ بَنِىٓ إِسۡرَٲٓءِيلَ عَنكَ إِذۡ جِئۡتَهُم بِٱلۡبَيِّنَـٰتِ فَقَالَ ٱلَّذِينَ كَفَرُواْ مِنۡہُمۡ إِنۡ هَـٰذَآ إِلَّا سِحۡرٌ۬ مُّبِينٌ۬ (١١٠)\n\n(Remember) when Allah will say (on the Day of Resurrection). "O 'Iesa (Jesus), son of Maryam (Mary)! Remember My Favour to you and to your mother when I supported you with Ruh-ul-Qudus [Jibrael (Gabriel)] so that you spoke to the people in the cradle and in maturity; and when I taught you writing, Al-Hikmah (the power of understanding), the Taurat (Torah) and the Injeel (Gospel); and when you made out of the clay, as it were, the figure of a bird, by My Permission, and you breathed into it, and it became a bird by My Permission, and you healed those born blind, and the lepers by My Permission, and when you brought forth the dead by My Permission; and when I restrained the Children of Israel from you (when they resolved to kill you) since you came unto them with clear proofs, and the disbelievers among them said: 'This is nothing but evident magic.' "\n\n[Sourate Al Mâ\'idah, 110]</string>
    <string name="correct_answer_15">ٱلۡحَمۡدُ لِلَّهِ ٱلَّذِى وَهَبَ لِى عَلَى ٱلۡكِبَرِ إِسۡمَـٰعِيلَ وَإِسۡحَـٰقَ‌ۚ إِنَّ رَبِّى لَسَمِيعُ ٱلدُّعَآءِ (٣٩) \n\n "All the praises and thanks be to Allah, Who has given me in old age Isma'il (Ishmael) and Ishaque (Isaac). Verily! My Lord is indeed the All-Hearer of invocations.(39)\n\n[Sourate Ibrâhîm, 39]</string>


</resources>